PRATEEK AGRAWAL

L +91 7464847884

□ prateekagrawal89760@gmail.com
□ bit.ly/prateekagrawal
□ Pune, India

TECHNICAL SKILLS



EDUCATION

B.Tech

GLA University

Computer Science CGPA- 7.2

Intermediate

UP Board

Percentage- 82

High School

UP Board

Percentage- 74

FIND ME ONLINE



@agrawal-prateek

Github

@agrawal-prateek

SUMMARY

Experienced in a product based company as Software Engineer, where my day to day responsibilities includes writing APIs & services, development of application frontend & standalone applications, and writing complex SQL queries.

I've strong OOP design skills, solid knowledge of system design, flexible in learning new technologies, experience with Agile & client-server architecture development, web applications, web services, restful APIs and passionate to work with architects on complex systems.

I have good problem solving skills and strong knowledge in algorithms & data structures.

EXPERIENCE

Media.net

Application Developer (Mar 2020 - Present)

Working on Vue and Java, and day to day responsibility includes creation of web application

Cloudreach

Software Engineer (Jan 2020 - Mar 2020)

Worked on pre-cloud, developed following feature:

- ☑ Created "upload CSV" feature for bulk update on asset and nodes for the cloud resources
- Writing Java services to be consumed by UI
- Conversion of Postgres procedures into Java services
- ☑ Created a helper service to validate the OS for "GCP Velostrata" for semistructured data without analytics

Software Developer (Jan 2019 - Jan 2020)

Worked on the following applications and features:

AWS Cost Explorer

Developed "AWS Cost Explorer" to be used to analyze cost, usage, and performance for AWS resources. The features includes-

- ☑ Developed Inventory Explorer, budget vs actual cost, and prebuilt top reports
- Feature for user-defined reports
- Worked on looker (A BI tool)
- Writing complex SQL queries

Hierarchy Builder

Developed "Hierarchy Builder" to manage user's cloud resources efficiently

- Developed delete, edit, creation of group and hierarchies for Hierarchy Builder
- Features for user assignment to the groups
- Developed features for spend management and Budget for cloud resources

Other tasks

Worked on some different tasks according to company's requirement

- Developed backend APIs using spring-boot to show data on different frontend applications including cost explorer and manage (A Cloudreach Application)
- Writing complex SQL with backend services
- ☑ Conversion of PL/SQL procedures into Java backend middleware
- ☑ Developed standalone application to run designer task on cloud using Python
- ☑ Big shoutout to company on completion 37 tasks within a sprint.

PROJECTS

Antitheft Pro [☑]

A security system which is **patented** and used Python to develop

Abacuscea [☑]

A website developed on Node.Js for hosting events and media

Robot 2

IoT project developed using Google APIs, Python

Credential Generator □

A web application developed for IIIT using PHP

Security system controller [□]

Web Application developed using Python and Flask

Cloud drive ☑

Linux software developed using Python

Grub modifier [☑]

Linux software developed using Python

Te Amo[□]

A restaurant website developed as a freelancer

LICENSES & CERTIFICATIONS

Google Cloud Platform Fundamentals: Core Infrastructure ✓

Coursera, Credential ID KV7EDLB59PMX

Acadmic Credential Generator <a>□

Credential ID IIITM/DIR/Reco/21042018

React - The Complete Guide(incl. React Router & Redux)[™]

Udemy, Credential ID UC-OI16WE9B

ACHIEVEMENTS

Owns a patented product Antitheft and received a fund of Rs 2.5 Lakhs from IEDC (Innovation and Entrepreneurship Development Centre).